ABODERIN MICHEAL

FRONT END ENGINEER

Lagos, Nigeria | (+234) 70-4213-7545 | abodmicheal@gmail.com | Personal Website | Linkedin | Github

Profile

Front End Engineer, React Redux and Javascript Developer with over 6 years of front end experience and a passion for responsive website design as well as building reusable component libraries for other developers and industries.

To deal with my insomnia, I began coding and ethical hacking at a young age. This gave me a lot of working hours and experience creating scalable projects, adding SEO features to React, working with lifecycles, and deploying numerous websites that received a lot of traffic and possitive feedback.

Skills

HTML, CSS, Material UI, JavaScript, React, Redux, Laravel, Git, Responsive Design, BEM, CMS, SEO, OOP, Technical Skills, Project Management Skills, Problem Solving Skills, Time Management Skills, Critical Thinking Skills, Decision Making Skills, Excellent Communication Skills, Organization Skills.

Employment History_

Build-It FULL-TIME

LEAD DEVELOPER (July 2022 - Present)

- Lead a team of developers to incorporate new React features to the website.
- Liaise with team leads across other departments to promote the company.
- Created a unique User Interface and Experience of visitors on the website.
- Designed, built, and configured website to meet company standards.
- Managed the general workflow of sub-developers.
- Translated a UI/UX design into code by building the UI part of the website using React and Redux.

REACT DEVELOPER (March 2022 - July 2022)

- Developed a web app on a Hive blockchain system using React.
- Optimized the page loading times.
- Incorporated new features to aid an incredible customer experience.

OneAlphaNg Logistics - Lagos, Nigeria

CONTRACT

June 2022 - Present

FRONT END DEVELOPER

- Built a logistics firm web app by converting the given UI/UX into code using Html, CSS, and J-Query.
- Researched relevant data along with the team leader to design the UI.
- Built the website from scratch, and included all relevant features to ensure a seamless User Experience.
- Included Flutterwave as the major payment gateway.

Plus One Technologies (NYSC) - Ibadan, Nigeria

INTERNSHIP

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT INTERSHIP

May 2022 - Presen

- Worked closely with a team of freelance developers to deliver high, quality content.
- Collaborated with other members of the team to build several demo e-commerce websites and pages.
- Learnt how to build multiple projects using React, J-Query, Redux, and HTML.

Batlan Superstore - Lagos, Nigeria

CONTRACT

June 2022- Presen

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Developed an e-commerce website from scratch using PHP Laravel, CSS, and J-Query.

- The User Interface, admin dashboard, and every e-commerce section was built accordingly using php blade.
- · Designed the User Interface and coded every e-commerce section accordingly.
- Linked website to Flutterwave and added bank transfer option to enable customers pay purchase their goods easily and fast.

Independent Freelancer REMOTE

FREELANCE FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

November 2020 - present

- Developed a web administrator for an existing ecommerce website using Laravel and Blade Template
- · Developed a full hotel booking website with login, registration, user dashboard and other functionalities using Laravel and Blade Template.

Independent Freelancer - Katy, Houston, Texas

FREELANCE FRONT END DEVELOPER

January 2016 - present

REMOTE

- · Built a portfolio website for a photographer using HTML, CSS, and JS, was hosted on Hostinger.
- Built a landing page using React, Material UI and I added the chat widget functionality using React chat widget package
- Developed a landing page for an interior designer using HTML, CSS, and JS.
- Translated a UI/UX design into code by building the UI part of an ecommerce web app using React and Redux.
- · Created numerous landing pages and portfolio websites Using HTML, CSS, and JS.

Personal Projects

Ecommerce web Application Demo

• Built a responsive ecommerce web application with user login ans registeration system using React, Redux, React Router, CSS anf Firebase

Home/Vacation Rentals Web Application UI Demo

GitHub

- Built a responsive Booking rentals with date features and product booking page
- · React, React Router, CSS, Material UI, JSON, Firebase, React Dates

Netflix UI Web Application Demo

GitHub

- Designed a responsive web application that looked like Netflix and I used Axios to consumed TMDB movie API.
- React, React Router, CSS, Material UI, Axios, Firebase, TMDB Movie API.

Education

McPherson University (MCU)

Lago-ibadan expresss,way, Nigeria September 2017 - August 2021

B.S.C in Computer Science

• Courses: OOP in Java, Compilers, Algorithms, Data Structure, Operating Systems